<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2022-07-28T01:43:59.181Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-07-28T01:43:59.181Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adventures in Krowne Keep: Actual play report(s) of the play by post group.]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/adventures-in-krowne-keep-actual-play.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/adventures-in-krowne-keep-actual-play.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-27T07:28:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adventures in Krowne Keep



 So, I've been taking some players through B2 - Keep on the Borderlands through play-by-post gaming. We use Discord for this and I'm constantly learning how to do this better. There have been two "sessions" this far, which I kind of classify as a separate excursion. Our playing mainly depends on me having the time and state of mind to run it, which means that it's usually a school vacation thing. We're also in quite different time zones, which makes it slower than it might otherwise be, but I've got nothing to complain about. The pace is right for me, going from about two posts a day to one every other day moves things about quickly enough to still feel like we're getting things done. The system we use is Maze Rats, which makes things go rather smoothly. Anyway…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kung-fu Training Minigame]]></title>
        <id>https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/07/kung-fu-training-minigame.html</id>
        <link href="https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/07/kung-fu-training-minigame.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-27T02:20:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As I said in my previous post, I've been watching a lot of kung fu movies. A core feature of these movies is a training scene. The hero goes from nursing their bruised knuckles to smashing through stone walls. Importantly, there are frequently multiple training scenes. 36 Chambers of Shaolin is essentially one long training scene sequence.
Because training scenes are an important part of the genre, they seem important to gameify. Saying "Okay, you go off and train for a few months and we're back" seems insufficient. 
But how can you make doing 100 pushups, reciting 100 sutras, or carrying 100 jugs of water interesting?


From Kill 6 Billion Demons


Honing Your Skills vs Learning New Skills
When training, you can hone your skills or learn new skills. 
Honing your skills allows you to impro…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rise Up Comus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shadow Appalachia: Boone Saltwoods]]></title>
        <id>https://d66kobolds.blogspot.com/2022/07/shadow-appalachia-boone-saltwoods.html</id>
        <link href="https://d66kobolds.blogspot.com/2022/07/shadow-appalachia-boone-saltwoods.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-26T18:32:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The salt came first, even before the coal. When the hollers were not yet born, the Iapetus Ocean covered everything. Some say the ancient blanket of buried salt keeps what shouldn't be out of the woods. Others say it subtly whispers to the Old Things, inviting them to the gullies and high places across West Virginia.
Down south of Charleston, past where the Kanawha River branches off into the trickle of Loop Creek, are the deep woods cramped-in around nowhere towns like Kinkaid and Artie. This was wild land even before I-64 was abandoned and fell apart under the forest canopy, and now it's all but primeval landscape, peppered with cabins and hunters and things best left alone.


Felix Riano - Artstation


Wandering through these parts might reveal (d20)...
1-4: d4 dump trucks. Belonging to…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>d66 Classless Kobolds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Father Clement Palacz, Curate of the Keep]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/meet-father-clement-palacz-curate-of.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/meet-father-clement-palacz-curate-of.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-26T06:00:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Father Clement Palacz
HP: 12 // ARMOR: 10 // ATTACK +1 // Miracles: 2 // STR: +2 // WIL: +3 //



"Der Kellermeister", by Max Thedy

It is known that Father Clement Palacz:
• Is not from around here, but people disagree on where he's actually from
• Is a man of great faith, who can perform miracles
• Has a patient and merciful outlook towards people, even enemies


It is said that Father Clement Palacz:
• Is a possible candidate to become the next Pope, should the current one die.
• Used to live in Moorish lands.
• Has a powerful relic in his possession.


When you meet Father Clement Palacz:
1. He will ask you how you are doing, and how he can help you.
2. He asks what your thoughts are about the last sermon he gave.
3. Asks you if you can help one of the people in this parish with a prob…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Midjourney Monday: Lamordian Money]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20380</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/25/midjourney-monday-lamordian-money/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-25T10:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using Midjourney to make Lamordian Bills for our Ravenloft gothic fantasy investigative game.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Orion Romatet: Advisor to the Castellan]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/meet-orion-romatet-advisor-to-castellan.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/meet-orion-romatet-advisor-to-castellan.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-25T05:29:00.005Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advisor: Orion Romatet
HP: 8 // ARMOR: 6 // SPELL SLOTS: 2 DEX +1 // WIL +2
Orion Romatet is the delicate, nine-fingered advisor to the Castellan.



Study Head of a Woman
Anthonis van Dyck

Orion Romatet is known to: 
• Be the personal Advisor to the Castellan.
 • Have only nine fingers. 
• Have a strong fashion sense.


Orion Romatet is rumored to:
• Actually be girl, disguised as a man so as to be able to be around the Castellan. Scandalous!
• Have sold his finger to the devil for dark, magical power. Why does he get away with this?
• Actually be a fairy prince, tagging along with the Castellan to see if a possible alliance would be a good idea.


Orion Romatet will ask you:
 • What your Zodiac Sign is.
• What strange things you have seen.
• Wether you could bring back something strange next time, preferably alive.


Gear:
Magical Plate Mail:
• +2 Armor
• no advantage on DEX Danger Rolls or Surprise Attack Rolls.
• Orichalcum armor inscribed with illusion runes, giving it the look of pretty, regular clothes.
Ring of the Phoenix:
• A ring holding a single feather from a phoenix’s tail. This gives free access to the word FIRE or LIFE for use in spells, wether or not the winds of magic or the pre-ordained position of the heavenly bodies would dictate it so. You can only choose one of the two words. You cannot use them both at once.
Short Bow:
• 2 handed weapon for shooting ranged arrows.
Magical Arrows (10): 
 • Contain their own spell slot each.
• One of the words is already set by the rune carved in the arrowhead (SHOOT/SHOOTING) the other depends on the winds of magic and a user of magic to fill in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nameless Legends of GLOG]]></title>
        <id>https://slightadjustments.blogspot.com/2022/07/nameless-legends-of-glog.html</id>
        <link href="https://slightadjustments.blogspot.com/2022/07/nameless-legends-of-glog.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-24T10:22:00.003Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a work in progress. Any part of a class marked with a ? is currently undecided. Any text after // is a comment, left for your consideration. Many classes are missing the higher level abilities. Several classes are missing quite a lot of necessary parts, and will be finished as needed.
The Fire Thief - Anato Finnstark

Recommended Rules
These are the rules I use. They work pretty well, but are tuned to my specific table. Hence, they are not The Rules, just recommended.

Spwack's Baseline GLOG Ruleset, using "Tragic" Death and Dismemberment
Shuffle the class list, and take a few off the top. Players then choose their class from this smaller selection
Players should not go through the entire list to choose a class, but if they have a specific concept in mind, they can search for the o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Slight Adjustments</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nameless Legends of GLOG]]></title>
        <id>https://slightadjustments.blogspot.com/2022/07/nameless-legends-of-glog.html</id>
        <link href="https://slightadjustments.blogspot.com/2022/07/nameless-legends-of-glog.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-24T10:22:00.003Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a work in progress. Any part of a class marked with a ? is currently undecided. Any text after // is a comment, left for your consideration. Many classes are missing the higher level abilities. Several classes are missing quite a lot of necessary parts, and will be finished as needed.
The Fire Thief - Anato Finnstark

Recommended Rules
These are the rules I use. They work pretty well, but are tuned to my specific table. Hence, they are not The Rules, just recommended.

Spwack's Baseline GLOG Ruleset, using "Tragic" Death and Dismemberment
Shuffle the class list, and take a few off the top. Players then choose their class from this smaller selection
Players should not go through the entire list to choose a class, but if they have a specific concept in mind, they can search for the o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Slight Adjustments</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Father Winoc Le Drôle: The Castellan's Scribe]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/meet-father-winoc-le-drole-castellans.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/meet-father-winoc-le-drole-castellans.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-24T05:45:00.006Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Father Winoc Le Drôle, Warrior Priest of Saint Martin and Scribe to the Castellan:
HP: 6 // ARMOR: 9 // Miracle Slot  // WIL +1 
A young, zealous and scrawny warrior priest on his way to holiness. 



"Portrait of a Young Benedictine" - Giovanni Francesco Caroto



Father Winoc Le Drôle is known to:

 • Be the personal Scribe to the Castellan due to his training in reading and writing, and his devotion making him trustworthy.
• Be a warrior-priest devoted to Saint-Martin. Devoted and Zealous in his protection of the weak.
 • Have accompanied the Castellan on at least one adventure before coming to the Keep.
Father Winoc Le Drôle is said to have:
• Spoken with angels.
• Broken his nose in a fistfight with the devil. Rumors cannot agree on who won.
• A jealous streak when it comes to friendships.
Father Winoc Le Drôle will ask you: 
• Your opinion on the parable of the good Samaritan. What would you do?
• To pray with him later, and seek the Lord’s counsel in routing this land of chaos.
• What sources of Chaos you have witnessed and where? Can you point to it on a map?
Gear:
Plate Mail:
 • +2 Armor 
• no advantage on DEX Danger Rolls or Surprise Attack Rolls. 
Shield:  
• +1 ARMOR (1 hand)
 Mace:
 • 1 hand
 Angel’s Promise:
• A shimmering feather, given by an angel in a vision with the promise of assisting in restraining an enemy once when called upon.
 • Enemy in question needs to make a Danger Roll + WIL or be paralyzed for the remainder of the scene.
 Holy Symbol:
Medallion of Saint Martin on a rosary. When brandished, it gives access to the word PROTECT for the use with Miracles.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer on Star Wars RPGs]]></title>
        <id>https://knightattheopera.blogspot.com/2022/07/a-primer-on-star-wars-rpgs.html</id>
        <link href="https://knightattheopera.blogspot.com/2022/07/a-primer-on-star-wars-rpgs.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-24T04:05:00.005Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you've received a link to this article, you may have just asked the question, "what's the deal with Star Wars RPGs?" The first part of this post is a succinct overview of all the major (and some minor) options out there which cover this need.
I decided to write this because in the last two weeks, I've seen at least 4 Reddit posts and a couple Discord messages where people asked that very question, and I get tired of explaining it. So if you see someone asking that question, link them to this article.



Outline
Firstly, there are (basically) three official Star Wars RPGs:


West End Games Star Wars (1987), AKA "Star Wars d6." This is the "old school" option and uses big pools of d6s for everything.
Wizards of the Coast Star Wars (2000), AKA "Star Wars d20," which was revised in 2002 and…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A Knight at the Opera</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet the Castellan: Morcant Dupoisson]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/meet-castellan-morcant-dupoisson.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/meet-castellan-morcant-dupoisson.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-23T05:50:00.005Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Council in the Keep is made up off the Castellan, his Scribe and his Advisor. They are working together to halt and defeat the forces of chaos trying to invade the lands through this little  fiefdom. The actual Count of the keep (Count Leopold de Chouxchaude) has gone missing, and the Castellan, his uncle on his mother’s side, has taken his place.



This is kind of what the Castellan looks like.
"The Prefect Raffaele Raggi", Van Dyck, c. 1625


The Castellan: Morcant Dupoisson
HP: 14 // ARMOR: 10 // ATT: +3 // WIL+2 // DEX+1 // STR: +2
Morcant Dupoisson is known to: 
• Have gone on many an adventure in his youth, all over Europe.
 • Be older than the count, but not by much, being one of the last children born in a long line, while the count is a first child of a first child
• Possess …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Misplaced Kingdom]]></title>
        <id>https://glassbirdgames.blogspot.com/2022/07/kornog-return-home.html</id>
        <link href="https://glassbirdgames.blogspot.com/2022/07/kornog-return-home.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-22T21:47:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inside the Forest, Under the Moonlight - Caspar Friedrich 1830

Once upon a time, as a younger, foolish man (like just over a year ago) I started a blog. There was a lot that went into that and a lot that led up to that, but let's leave it at this: it was something I'd always wanted to do, and getting emotional and writing nerd shit remains something I want to pour myself into for a lot more years.
(The next few paragraphs are some more weepy personal blather because apparently this blog also doubles as therapy for me, so feel free to skip down to the title below. TL;DR: here's a project I've been toying with and plan to start working on in earnest.)
I set myself some rules/goals/principles when I got started. I called them The Cares of a Carelord, which I still think is a pretty good desc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Glass Bird Games</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Killer Bees]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-killer-bees.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-killer-bees.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-22T05:19:00.011Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On killer bees
HP: 1 // ARMOR: 7 // Special: Dies after stinging // Fast fliers.
 “Jupiter, king of the Roman gods, is said to have given the honeybee his stinger, to protect his honey. His wife, Juno, however, insisted there must be payment for this gift of a weapon, so Jupiter gave the stinger with the condition that the bee dies should she use it.”



Image by rawpixel.com



Bees the size of loaves of bread are sometimes spotted around the borderlands. But where do they come from? Where do they find the nectar for their honey?
Where do they come from?
1. Deep underground, where there are giant caves full of giant animals and plants. 
They are lost and confused. This upsets them greatly. A system of caves must be close by that leads to these strange lands. Their honey has natural healin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[So you took to the road in the Borderlands (Encounter Table)]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/so-you-took-to-road-in-borderlands.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/so-you-took-to-road-in-borderlands.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-21T10:34:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So you took to the road in the Borderlands...
This is a dangerous thing to do, and we're playing Maze Rats, so make a Danger Roll! 
If there's any reason for you gaining advantage or adding a stat bonus, argue for it now.
Whether or not you succeed, an encounter will be had. The result of your danger roll just decides how well your encounter will go. 



Pilgrims arriving in Rome for the first Jubilee in 1300, from Giovanni Sercambi’s “Chronicles,” around 1400.
Credit...Archivio di Stato, Lucca

After the Danger Roll has been rolled, the GM also rolls 2d6, basing the encounter table on this blogpost by Papers and Pencils, adding, consequently a dragon and a wizard (or in this case, witch) to the module. Also, not wanting to throw away a roll if the danger roll was successful, I have two en…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 FIST Characters]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/07/5-fist-characters.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/07/5-fist-characters.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-20T21:07:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've been growing interested in FIST, a rules-light RPG with a very Metal Gear Solid vibe, but in a way that feels true to Kojima and not just derivative, and taking other influences from the likes of Lovecraft, GI Joe, and Doom Patrol, which of course drew my attention even before I saw it referenced as an inspiration.


I may want to do a bigger FIST post down the line, or maybe a micro-setting using FIST as the core system, but in the mean time, here is my attempt at a few premade characters randomly generated:





Codename: Anti-Mutant P
Tachyonic "mutant" whose DNA was chipped and blasted with psychonine, the nucleotide from the center of all spacetimes, reduced like a block of marble into the teleological True One towards which all life unknowingly aspires. It modulates itself with …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Wolves]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-wolves.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-wolves.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-20T06:55:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Wolves
HP: 3, ARMOR 6, ATT+1


Wolves in the Borderlands are common. They roam the forests in packs. While the North American wolves might be known to be afraid of humans in general, the European wolves are bigger and meaner than that and have been known to attack humans when hungry. 


In the Borderlands, the strange and chaotic forces that permeate this area sometimes changes things about the wolves and make them strange.


The chance of this alteration occurring will depend on how much of a foothold chaos has on the lands. I suggest starting with a 1/6 chance, triggering on a 6, adding +1 to each time ‘regular’ wolves are rolled. And add a +1 for each rank of a foothold Chaos has on the lands.






The Eurasian Grey Wolf, found free to use on Wikipedia



The Wolves of the Borderland might…
1. Talk and understand humans. They know to use this to attract prey.
2. Leave ashen paw prints that remain warm to the touch for a night and a day.
3. Have a howl that makes you think your feet suddenly sink into the ground and are stuck.  
Roll DANGER +WIL or be paralyzed with fear for a round.
4. Have the ability to grow to the size of cows.
Double HP, +1 to ATTACK
5. Be ridden by kobolds wanting to cause mischief of the deadly kind. 
They will use their own devious skills to make fighting harder, like riding with a line of rope between them to try and trip up people, shooting arrows that might paralyze or put you to sleep, etc.
6. Have the ability to breathe a cloud of mist, making ranged attacks on them harder, forcing people to have to go hand to hand, or to make it easier for them to flee.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meditating on the White Lotus]]></title>
        <id>https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/07/meditating-on-white-lotus.html</id>
        <link href="https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/07/meditating-on-white-lotus.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-19T12:00:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes I make kung fu posts. I've started using the `kung-fu` label to aggregate them. Click on this label to read my other mutterings on this subject.
I've been watching Shaw Brothers films at the gym this summer. If you're unfamiliar, Shaw Brothers was a prolific Hong Kong production company that produced grindhouse kung fu films. Basically, all the audio samples from Enter the Wu-Tang (36 Chambers) were from these films. 
> Frog style is incredibly strong and immune to nearly any weapon.
I like some of the films more than I like others, but almost all of them have something that made me say "Ha ha neat." Almost all of them have something gameable. 
In this post, I'm going to step through the Shaw Brothers' film Clan of the White Lotus beat by beat. Heavy spoilers warning, obviously. …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rise Up Comus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Magobia the Witch]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/meet-magobia-witch.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/meet-magobia-witch.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-19T08:10:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet the Witch Magobia:
Mother to goblins and hobgoblins


Trying to find a source for this picture led me to a deactivated Tumblr for Cultur Tava.



HP:4 // ARMOR 6* (impervious to physical harm until a certain protection is dealt with)
SPELL SLOTS: 5 // Special Item: Cursing Charm


It is said that the witch Magobia cannot have children of her own and that because of that she resolved to steal babies for her own. 
• Some say that it’s because she’s barren, some say that it’s because she’s too mean for anyone to want a relationship with her.  
• Rumor goes that her desire for children has led her to kidnapping them and feeding them her special witch-food, turning them into goblins and hobgoblins in the process. 
 • She is followed around by what looks like a black cat that has the power,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bring the Page With You]]></title>
        <id>https://www.hypertextfish.org/bring-the-page</id>
        <link href="https://www.hypertextfish.org/bring-the-page"/>
        <updated>2022-07-18T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a proof of concept for a worldbuilding game based on the world of Myst. Using these rules you can create and detail your own ages.
Bring the page with you is based on games like Microscope and I’m sorry did you say street magic. To play this game you will need some index cards and writing tools.
Setup
Before you start exploring the Ages, establish the basics of your setting.
First agree on the tone of your world. Is it an eerie lonely experience? Or are the ages still bustling with life? Decide with your group and note down a couple of adjectives.
Create a foundational age and a device (following their respective instructions in the next chapter). Describe why this age serves as a crossroads to other ages. Name this age.
Play passes clockwise. Each player may add either an age or a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bring the Page With You</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monday Midjourney: Doorways]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20334</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/18/monday-midjourney-doorways/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making dungeon doors for dungeon delving fantasy role-playing games, like Dungeons and Dragons with Midjourney]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Gros Jean: Ogre of the Woods]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/meet-gros-jean-ogre-of-woods.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/meet-gros-jean-ogre-of-woods.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-18T09:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google tells me this image is from Game of Thrones



Gros Jean: Ogre of the woods
HP:12, ARMOR:8, +2AB, STR+2, Ogre Great-Club (2-handed, Ogre Sized, +1DMG), Wearing treated bearskin as armour (+1ARM, already calculated)


Gros Jean is the ogre that roams these parts of the country. He mainly works as a mercenary for the forces of Chaos. He recently has come in possession of an unholy symbol of the dark forces, that will slowly corrupt his mind, offering him dark powers. Gros Jean has an agreement with the Witch Magobia that if the goblins pay him, he will protect them, as he can have some of the babies she brings in as food.


When Gros Jean is met in the wild he…
 1. Is eating and will tolerate weary travelers to join. 
2. Is admiring his ruby necklace of the Snake.
 3. Has a manacled prisoner on a chain and is sitting down with a pensive smile brainstorming on an apt punishment for the oath the prisoner broke. 
4. Is very hungry and looking for food. You look tasty. Or do you perhaps have a baby?
 5. Is grumpy and angry because his prisoner escaped. 
6. Is hanging chains with stone skulls on them on a prisoner. One for each of the men he promised to bring back safely, but failed to do so. He has to cary these around wherever they go.


Ogres are descendants of the old Roman deity called Orcus. They roam the world, eating babies (preferably) and enjoying in punishing oath-breakers. 


There are more ogres in the land, but not a lot. They do not get along very much and as such remain a good distance away from each other. If they get too close to each other, the land cannot sustain their appetite all that much and they will fight over food. Sometimes an ogre will find a mate though, and somehow they manage to tolerate each other. Woe betide the lands where this is the case.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ten Interesting Traps]]></title>
        <id>https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/07/ten-interesting-traps.html</id>
        <link href="https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/07/ten-interesting-traps.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-18T02:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There have been many posts on this subject. This is mine.
(Because of His Majesty the Worm, I find myself in the position where I need to explain concepts in a worse way than the originator of the idea. I am standing on the shoulders of giants and falling.)
---


Art for HIS MAJESTY THE WORM by Marcin S

Put some of these traps into your dungeons. Use them as inspiration to create your own.
 I. Mysterious Tower, Acid Lake
 There is a tumbledown tower on the middle of an island. The island is in the middle of a bright-green acid lake. The lake is death for whoever falls into it.
 Why this trap doesn’t suck: The possible rewards are tantalizing. (A mysterious tower? What’s in it?) The dangers are obvious. (The lake is bright green! Acid is deadly!) This is an open-ended problem with many pos…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rise Up Comus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Primal Quest – Hunting the Sky Wizards]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20300</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/17/primal-quest/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-18T00:02:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In which I gathered with Stras, Jay and Sean in order to hunt sky wizards with the NSR Stone and Sorcery adventure game, Primal Quest.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[6 – Time, Trophy Gold: Roots of Old Kalduhr]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20278</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/16/6-time-trophy-gold-roots-of-old-kalduhr/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-16T17:25:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this session of the table-top role-playing game, Trophy Gold we playtested a surreal incursion I'm writing called Attack of the Phase Spider.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Hobgoblins]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-hobgoblins.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-hobgoblins.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-16T10:37:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some more goblins from Jim Henson's 'Labyrinth'.



Hobgoblins: 
HP: 4 // ARMOR 6
Hobgoblins were once children who showed a definite mean streak in their nature. The Witch Magobia lured them away from home with many promises, and fed them her special food, disguised as gingerbread cakes. Eventually her corruption deformed them as well. 
The following are all true: 
• Once the gingerbread is eaten, they can no longer get sustenance from any other food. They need her food to survive. This is how she controls them.
 • These children grow up looking like very wrinkly teenagers in much the same way as the babies turn into goblins. Their skin-tone remains closer to their original one, if not a bit less vibrant.
• The hobgoblins are cruel and have less of a need to be fearful, compared to the go…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weird North is now available IN PRINT!]]></title>
        <id>https://d66kobolds.blogspot.com/2022/07/weird-north-is-now-available-in-print.html</id>
        <link href="https://d66kobolds.blogspot.com/2022/07/weird-north-is-now-available-in-print.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T19:51:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Title.
With the excellent aid of Jacob Marks, Weird North is not only formatted for print (finally, I know, I know) but already available for purchase from Lulu.com as a high-quality stapled softcover digest book. It's quite nice. As always, "WELCOME15" should work as a discount code, or the other various-and-often discount codes which Lulu spits out on the regular.
Storefront Link]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>d66 Classless Kobolds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cthulhu Style Investigations]]></title>
        <id>http://technoskald.me/?p=6440</id>
        <link href="https://technoskald.me/2022/07/15/cthulhu-style-investigations/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T19:12:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last year or two, I’ve played a good bit of Call of Cthulhu and related games. While I love many things about that particular game, I don’t like the crunchiness of the character sheet. Investigators have nine attributes before we even get to things like Sanity, Luck, Magic Points, and skills! One thing … Continue reading Cthulhu Style Investigations →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kyle Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Goblins]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-goblins.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-goblins.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Goblins in the movie Labyrinth, by Jim Henson. Part of the inspiration.

 
Goblins: 
HP: 2 // ARMOR 6
stats for Maze Rats


It is true that Goblins were children stolen from their crib and turned into goblins by the Witch Magobia. The following is also true about them:
• They never grow bigger than a toddler, as their growth is stunted by their strange diet.
• Their skin gets an unhealthy grey and wrinkles as if they are of very old age. Their pupils turn a very pale-pink color and their hair a greasy black.
 • Most grow up to be mean, fearful and craven.


When encountering Goblins in the wild they… 
• Try to hide or run away if you are stronger than them. 
• Are singing a dreadful song that teaches to be mean. 
• Are carrying a stolen baby and arguing about who has to take care of it.


…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gloomwrought: City of Midnight, Session 3, The Second Wave]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20242</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/14/gloomwrought-city-of-midnight-session-3-the-second-wave/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T02:31:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In tonight's Thursday night Dungeons and Dragons game...the Sigil 6 loot the vault of the late vampire gang, kill the last surviving vampire, stuff 2 vampire spawn accountants in a bag of holding and face Innistradi Vampire Assassins.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rant: I'm Fucking Sick Of Stats]]></title>
        <id>https://eskur.dev/posts/rant-im-fucking-sick-of-stats/</id>
        <link href="https://eskur.dev/posts/rant-im-fucking-sick-of-stats/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My issues with player-facing stats and modifiers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>eskur.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Dreams about Journeys Through the Radiant Citadel]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20230</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/14/digital-dreams-about-journeys-through-the-radiant-citadel/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-14T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI Art inspired by the latest Dungeons and Dragons adventure book, Journeys Through the Radiant Citadel.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Fire Beetles]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-fire-beetles.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-fire-beetles.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-14T10:32:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm running the Borderlands via play-by-post over discord, and I'm using Maze Rats to do it. I like how it gives me extra incentive to reinvent things as I have to convert things anyway. One of these things is that I've been thinking about Fire Beetles and how they might be regarded in my take on a setting, a Medieval France type deal, where all the weird stuff is actually still weird. And I want to keep it that way. Things should be mysterious and unexplainable. I was first thinking of expanding the bugs into stages of life etc. but decided not to do that. Anyway, this is my first draft.

art by Caeora on Deviantart. - Not entirely how I envision it, but close enough for this article.
On Fire Beetles:
ARMOR:6 // HP:4
Fire beetles are:
• As large as a small dog or a big house-cat.
 • Live …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aboraz, the Striding Skull, The Tomb that Walks]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20216</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/13/aboraz-the-striding-skull-the-tomb-that-walks/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-13T19:18:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The unholy marriage of a Demi-Lich and an Iron Golem for our Thursday night Dungeons and Dragons game.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Band Of Blades]]></title>
        <id>http://hamsterhoard.home.blog/?p=1060</id>
        <link href="https://hamsterhoard.home.blog/2022/07/13/band-of-blades/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-13T17:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone likes having npcs to help, hinder, surprise, behind, or ambush the player characters. Everyone (well, a decent chunk of everyone, anyway) likes magic swords. Let’s combine them! :D! Presented here are a dozen sentient, sapient swords. They all have names along with titles; they have personalities, and some magical abilities, and some areas of … Continue reading Band Of Blades →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>taichara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Encounter Checklist]]></title>
        <id>5fc42d3b9955c744b550776c:5fc449cf7acac6192a4958a4:62cb05ac3e7e3277ca811061</id>
        <link href="https://www.prismaticwasteland.com/blog/encounter-checklist"/>
        <updated>2022-07-12T12:57:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A checklist you can use to improve your TTRPG encounters.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>W. F. Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Environmental Storytelling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.hypertextfish.org/env-story</id>
        <link href="https://www.hypertextfish.org/env-story"/>
        <updated>2022-07-12T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Image: still from the film Solaris (1974). Kris is trying to figure out what happened on the research station.
In this post I wanted to talk about using objects and locations in RPGs to tell a history or fiction. I believe we already use environmental storytelling in our games, however I wanted to delve deeper—understand how we can consciously apply this concept to our settings.
Motivation
The OSR play culture is particularly interested in exploring fantastical locations. Lots of focus is put into creating these spaces that the referee describes to the players. In turn, the players are expected to interact in these spaces as much as possible. Players usually explore ruins or derelicts of some kind, so the objects within them will always have a history.
If you are playing a mystery game, en…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Environmental Storytelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 2nd Age is here]]></title>
        <id>https://tabletopcuriositycabinet.blogspot.com/2022/07/the-2nd-age-is-here.html</id>
        <link href="https://tabletopcuriositycabinet.blogspot.com/2022/07/the-2nd-age-is-here.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-10T17:57:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first part of the project Adventures Buffo and I have been working on is complete. I originally approached Adventures Buffo after reading a great blogpost of his asking if he minded if I took a stab at the idea. Instead, he proposed we attempted something colleboratively and this is the result:



The 2nd Age 

The 2nd Age is a tabletop RPG supplement containing 12 institutions intended to supplant traditional classes for games that prefer a more materialist approach to advancement. 
When using these institutions, power is gained primarily as a reward for your service to the empire of Turandor through one of its institutions. However, once you join one of these organisations, they decide what you do and where you go. Those who serve their institution will advance through its ranks and …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tabletop Curiosity Cabinet</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MRD2 PR 4: Political Intrigue in Non-Violent Dimensions]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/07/mrd2-pr-4-political-intrigue-in-non.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/07/mrd2-pr-4-political-intrigue-in-non.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T17:40:00.003Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was worried how this session would go, because there was very little in the way of "encounters" in the traditional sense or anything that would require them to use their character sheets, and a FUCKTON of NPCs and logistics. But it went better than I could have hoped. This was some good Social Intrigue, which I am all about. I don't know how well this will translate to a PR, despite my efforts to make these PRs more interesting.


I was inspired by the Scales of Conviction system for the videogame Triangle Strategy, where key plot events are decided on a vote, and the player has to talk to the various NPCs and gather information to try to sway the votes of the rest of the party. I figured that would work even better in a TTRPG, and it did. At some point either here or on Iconoclastic Flo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Case for Winged Spacecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.hypertextfish.org/space-wings</id>
        <link href="https://www.hypertextfish.org/space-wings"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A short post explaining why I think spaceships with wings can work in a hard sci-fi setting. And I will not be talking about landings here, since wings aren’t crucial for that. Instead I will introduce you to the concept of aerogravity assist.
Not to be confused with aerobreaking, which is a manoeuvre that uses the atmosphere of a planet to slow down a spacecraft. Aerogravity assist uses the atmosphere to speed up instead.
A common manoeuvre in space travel is the gravity assist—using a planets gravity well as a slingshot to deflect your trajectory. The closer you get to the planet, the more your course will be changed. The issue is that you are limited by the planets atmosphere. If you come too close, the drag will significantly reduce your speed and the costs will outweigh the benefits.
…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A Case for Winged Spacecraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gloomwrought: City of Midnight, Session 2, Killing Rahadin]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20201</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/07/gloomwrought-city-of-midnight-session-2-killing-rahadin/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T02:47:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In tonight's Thursday night Dungeons and Dragons game...the Sigil 6 kill Rahadin and most of her vampire gang that has terrorized the streets of Gloomwrought since Strahd's curse was lifted.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[emberlight] Pasts, Professions and Small Precious Things]]></title>
        <id>http://hamsterhoard.home.blog/?p=1057</id>
        <link href="https://hamsterhoard.home.blog/2022/07/05/emberlight-pasts-professions-and-small-precious-things/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-05T11:49:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Even in the remains of the world, people have something — someone — that they are, or were, or claimed to be. Or want to be. And everyone has a place they came from, even if they don’t want to stay there; and bits of that get carried forward as they forge ahead with a … Continue reading [emberlight] Pasts, Professions and Small Precious Things →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>taichara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GItMS! Mecha Gear]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/07/gitms-mecha-gear.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/07/gitms-mecha-gear.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-03T17:12:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is an old draft, way before I decided to start using Concept Crafting for Mecha Gear. I think in all likelihood it's too fiddly, and I wasn't satisfied with it even at the time, but it's interesting seeing how it got me to where it is now.




This is for my Into the Odd Mecha Hack: Get Into the Machine, Shinji! The mechanics have changed to varying degrees since I've been running my MRD2 Campaign, but this post more so corresponds to the original GitMS! than to MRD2. Most notably, it is no longer the case in MRD2 that Golem (the Mecha) have their own Ability Scores anymore, instead just sharing the pilot Ability Scores, but having their own Damage dice and of course the Gear.
Here's my Weird & Wonderful Table of Super Robot Wars-inspired Mecha and a "Gacha" Mecha Dispenser generator …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[d100 - Where Is The Key For This Locked Door?]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.d4caltrops.com/2022/07/d100-where-is-key-for-this-locked-door.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.d4caltrops.com/2022/07/d100-where-is-key-for-this-locked-door.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-03T16:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Locked Doors or Containers are a time-honored obstacle to exploration and discovery. They present an opportunity for the clever Thief to fiddle with their tools to flex their percentiles, the Fighter to muscle things open with a sturdy d6, or the Magic User to unleash a mighty Knock. If only there were another way?
 The presence of a Lock implies the existence of a Key. Here are a Hundred places where that pesky unlocker might live. Much like my previous posts on Secret or Stuck Doors, some imply a puzzle or a skosh of Set Dressing as well. Some of the particularly tricky ones might be worthy of rewarding the Players with a passe-partout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>d4 Caltrops</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Traits of the Mythic Underworld]]></title>
        <id>https://knightattheopera.blogspot.com/2022/07/traits-of-mythic-underworld.html</id>
        <link href="https://knightattheopera.blogspot.com/2022/07/traits-of-mythic-underworld.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T18:10:00.005Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The "Mythic Underworld" is a term popular in the OSR that I believe was coined by Jason Cone in Philotomy's Musings. Cone argued that the rules of OD&D can be interpreted to suggest that the "dungeons" that adventurers delve into aren't really to be understood as real, logical spaces created by normal people or natural processes. Rather, they're more like a surreal, dreamlike, and hostile realm that runs on its own twisted logic, which might be inconsistent. It gives the referee some leeway to make a contrived, game-y, "funhouse" dungeon instead of stressing about accuracy or rationality.

Much of what Cone describes are just traits of megadungeons, or even simply dungeons in general. Things like, "non-linear pathways" and "lots of connections between levels" aren't really mythic, they're …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A Knight at the Opera</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Every so often the best game is no game.]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20187</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/06/30/every-so-often-the-best-game-is-no-game/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T01:25:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In which a session of our D&D game is cancelled and we just chatted it up and enjoyed each other's faces.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>