<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2022-07-17T01:51:02.128Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-07-17T01:51:02.128Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[6 – Time, Trophy Gold: Roots of Old Kalduhr]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20278</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/16/6-time-trophy-gold-roots-of-old-kalduhr/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-16T17:25:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this session of the table-top role-playing game, Trophy Gold we playtested a surreal incursion I'm writing called Attack of the Phase Spider.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Hobgoblins]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-hobgoblins.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-hobgoblins.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-16T10:37:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some more goblins from Jim Henson's 'Labyrinth'.



Hobgoblins: 
HP: 4 // ARMOR 6
Hobgoblins were once children who showed a definite mean streak in their nature. The Witch Magobia lured them away from home with many promises, and fed them her special food, disguised as gingerbread cakes. Eventually her corruption deformed them as well. 
The following are all true: 
• Once the gingerbread is eaten, they can no longer get sustenance from any other food. They need her food to survive. This is how she controls them.
 • These children grow up looking like very wrinkly teenagers in much the same way as the babies turn into goblins. Their skin-tone remains closer to their original one, if not a bit less vibrant.
• The hobgoblins are cruel and have less of a need to be fearful, compared to the go…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weird North is now available IN PRINT!]]></title>
        <id>https://d66kobolds.blogspot.com/2022/07/weird-north-is-now-available-in-print.html</id>
        <link href="https://d66kobolds.blogspot.com/2022/07/weird-north-is-now-available-in-print.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T19:51:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Title.
With the excellent aid of Jacob Marks, Weird North is not only formatted for print (finally, I know, I know) but already available for purchase from Lulu.com as a high-quality stapled softcover digest book. It's quite nice. As always, "WELCOME15" should work as a discount code, or the other various-and-often discount codes which Lulu spits out on the regular.
Storefront Link]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>d66 Classless Kobolds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cthulhu Style Investigations]]></title>
        <id>http://technoskald.me/?p=6440</id>
        <link href="https://technoskald.me/2022/07/15/cthulhu-style-investigations/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T19:12:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last year or two, I’ve played a good bit of Call of Cthulhu and related games. While I love many things about that particular game, I don’t like the crunchiness of the character sheet. Investigators have nine attributes before we even get to things like Sanity, Luck, Magic Points, and skills! One thing … Continue reading Cthulhu Style Investigations →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kyle Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Goblins]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-goblins.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-goblins.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Goblins in the movie Labyrinth, by Jim Henson. Part of the inspiration.

 
Goblins: 
HP: 2 // ARMOR 6
stats for Maze Rats


It is true that Goblins were children stolen from their crib and turned into goblins by the Witch Magobia. The following is also true about them:
• They never grow bigger than a toddler, as their growth is stunted by their strange diet.
• Their skin gets an unhealthy grey and wrinkles as if they are of very old age. Their pupils turn a very pale-pink color and their hair a greasy black.
 • Most grow up to be mean, fearful and craven.


When encountering Goblins in the wild they… 
• Try to hide or run away if you are stronger than them. 
• Are singing a dreadful song that teaches to be mean. 
• Are carrying a stolen baby and arguing about who has to take care of it.


…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gloomwrought: City of Midnight, Session 3, The Second Wave]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20242</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/14/gloomwrought-city-of-midnight-session-3-the-second-wave/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T02:31:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In tonight's Thursday night Dungeons and Dragons game...the Sigil 6 loot the vault of the late vampire gang, kill the last surviving vampire, stuff 2 vampire spawn accountants in a bag of holding and face Innistradi Vampire Assassins.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rant: I'm Fucking Sick Of Stats]]></title>
        <id>https://eskur.dev/posts/rant-im-fucking-sick-of-stats/</id>
        <link href="https://eskur.dev/posts/rant-im-fucking-sick-of-stats/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My issues with player-facing stats and modifiers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>eskur.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Dreams about Journeys Through the Radiant Citadel]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20230</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/14/digital-dreams-about-journeys-through-the-radiant-citadel/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-14T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI Art inspired by the latest Dungeons and Dragons adventure book, Journeys Through the Radiant Citadel.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Fire Beetles]]></title>
        <id>https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-fire-beetles.html</id>
        <link href="https://thebeardedbelgiansplayground.blogspot.com/2022/07/on-fire-beetles.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-14T10:32:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm running the Borderlands via play-by-post over discord, and I'm using Maze Rats to do it. I like how it gives me extra incentive to reinvent things as I have to convert things anyway. One of these things is that I've been thinking about Fire Beetles and how they might be regarded in my take on a setting, a Medieval France type deal, where all the weird stuff is actually still weird. And I want to keep it that way. Things should be mysterious and unexplainable. I was first thinking of expanding the bugs into stages of life etc. but decided not to do that. Anyway, this is my first draft.

art by Caeora on Deviantart. - Not entirely how I envision it, but close enough for this article.
On Fire Beetles:
ARMOR:6 // HP:4
Fire beetles are:
• As large as a small dog or a big house-cat.
 • Live …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Bearded Belgian's Playground</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aboraz, the Striding Skull, The Tomb that Walks]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20216</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/13/aboraz-the-striding-skull-the-tomb-that-walks/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-13T19:18:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The unholy marriage of a Demi-Lich and an Iron Golem for our Thursday night Dungeons and Dragons game.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Band Of Blades]]></title>
        <id>http://hamsterhoard.home.blog/?p=1060</id>
        <link href="https://hamsterhoard.home.blog/2022/07/13/band-of-blades/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-13T17:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone likes having npcs to help, hinder, surprise, behind, or ambush the player characters. Everyone (well, a decent chunk of everyone, anyway) likes magic swords. Let’s combine them! :D! Presented here are a dozen sentient, sapient swords. They all have names along with titles; they have personalities, and some magical abilities, and some areas of … Continue reading Band Of Blades →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>taichara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Encounter Checklist]]></title>
        <id>5fc42d3b9955c744b550776c:5fc449cf7acac6192a4958a4:62cb05ac3e7e3277ca811061</id>
        <link href="https://www.prismaticwasteland.com/blog/encounter-checklist"/>
        <updated>2022-07-12T12:57:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A checklist you can use to improve your TTRPG encounters.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>W. F. Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Environmental Storytelling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.hypertextfish.org/env-story</id>
        <link href="https://www.hypertextfish.org/env-story"/>
        <updated>2022-07-12T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Image: still from the film Solaris (1974). Kris is trying to figure out what happened on the research station.
In this post I wanted to talk about using objects and locations in RPGs to tell a history or fiction. I believe we already use environmental storytelling in our games, however I wanted to delve deeper—understand how we can consciously apply this concept to our settings.
Motivation
The OSR play culture is particularly interested in exploring fantastical locations. Lots of focus is put into creating these spaces that the referee describes to the players. In turn, the players are expected to interact in these spaces as much as possible. Players usually explore ruins or derelicts of some kind, so the objects within them will always have a history.
If you are playing a mystery game, en…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Environmental Storytelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 2nd Age is here]]></title>
        <id>https://tabletopcuriositycabinet.blogspot.com/2022/07/the-2nd-age-is-here.html</id>
        <link href="https://tabletopcuriositycabinet.blogspot.com/2022/07/the-2nd-age-is-here.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-10T17:57:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first part of the project Adventures Buffo and I have been working on is complete. I originally approached Adventures Buffo after reading a great blogpost of his asking if he minded if I took a stab at the idea. Instead, he proposed we attempted something colleboratively and this is the result:



The 2nd Age 

The 2nd Age is a tabletop RPG supplement containing 12 institutions intended to supplant traditional classes for games that prefer a more materialist approach to advancement. 
When using these institutions, power is gained primarily as a reward for your service to the empire of Turandor through one of its institutions. However, once you join one of these organisations, they decide what you do and where you go. Those who serve their institution will advance through its ranks and …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tabletop Curiosity Cabinet</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MRD2 PR 4: Political Intrigue in Non-Violent Dimensions]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/07/mrd2-pr-4-political-intrigue-in-non.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/07/mrd2-pr-4-political-intrigue-in-non.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T17:40:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was worried how this session would go, because there was very little in the way of "encounters" in the traditional sense or anything that would require them to use their character sheets, and a FUCKTON of NPCs and logistics. But it went better than I could have hoped. This was some good Social Intrigue, which I am all about. I don't know how well this will translate to a PR, despite my efforts to make these PRs more interesting.


I was inspired by the Scales of Conviction system for the videogame Triangle Strategy, where key plot events are decided on a vote, and the player has to talk to the various NPCs and gather information to try to sway the votes of the rest of the party. I figured that would work even better in a TTRPG, and it did. At some point either here or on Iconoclastic Flo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Case for Winged Spacecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.hypertextfish.org/space-wings</id>
        <link href="https://www.hypertextfish.org/space-wings"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A short post explaining why I think spaceships with wings can work in a hard sci-fi setting. And I will not be talking about landings here, since wings aren’t crucial for that. Instead I will introduce you to the concept of aerogravity assist.
Not to be confused with aerobreaking, which is a manoeuvre that uses the atmosphere of a planet to slow down a spacecraft. Aerogravity assist uses the atmosphere to speed up instead.
A common manoeuvre in space travel is the gravity assist—using a planets gravity well as a slingshot to deflect your trajectory. The closer you get to the planet, the more your course will be changed. The issue is that you are limited by the planets atmosphere. If you come too close, the drag will significantly reduce your speed and the costs will outweigh the benefits.
…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A Case for Winged Spacecraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gloomwrought: City of Midnight, Session 2, Killing Rahadin]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20201</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/07/07/gloomwrought-city-of-midnight-session-2-killing-rahadin/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T02:47:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In tonight's Thursday night Dungeons and Dragons game...the Sigil 6 kill Rahadin and most of her vampire gang that has terrorized the streets of Gloomwrought since Strahd's curse was lifted.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[emberlight] Pasts, Professions and Small Precious Things]]></title>
        <id>http://hamsterhoard.home.blog/?p=1057</id>
        <link href="https://hamsterhoard.home.blog/2022/07/05/emberlight-pasts-professions-and-small-precious-things/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-05T11:49:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Even in the remains of the world, people have something — someone — that they are, or were, or claimed to be. Or want to be. And everyone has a place they came from, even if they don’t want to stay there; and bits of that get carried forward as they forge ahead with a … Continue reading [emberlight] Pasts, Professions and Small Precious Things →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>taichara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GItMS! Mecha Gear]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/07/gitms-mecha-gear.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/07/gitms-mecha-gear.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-03T17:12:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is an old draft, way before I decided to start using Concept Crafting for Mecha Gear. I think in all likelihood it's too fiddly, and I wasn't satisfied with it even at the time, but it's interesting seeing how it got me to where it is now.




This is for my Into the Odd Mecha Hack: Get Into the Machine, Shinji! The mechanics have changed to varying degrees since I've been running my MRD2 Campaign, but this post more so corresponds to the original GitMS! than to MRD2. Most notably, it is no longer the case in MRD2 that Golem (the Mecha) have their own Ability Scores anymore, instead just sharing the pilot Ability Scores, but having their own Damage dice and of course the Gear.
Here's my Weird & Wonderful Table of Super Robot Wars-inspired Mecha and a "Gacha" Mecha Dispenser generator …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[d100 - Where Is The Key For This Locked Door?]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.d4caltrops.com/2022/07/d100-where-is-key-for-this-locked-door.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.d4caltrops.com/2022/07/d100-where-is-key-for-this-locked-door.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-03T16:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Locked Doors or Containers are a time-honored obstacle to exploration and discovery. They present an opportunity for the clever Thief to fiddle with their tools to flex their percentiles, the Fighter to muscle things open with a sturdy d6, or the Magic User to unleash a mighty Knock. If only there were another way?
 The presence of a Lock implies the existence of a Key. Here are a Hundred places where that pesky unlocker might live. Much like my previous posts on Secret or Stuck Doors, some imply a puzzle or a skosh of Set Dressing as well. Some of the particularly tricky ones might be worthy of rewarding the Players with a passe-partout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>d4 Caltrops</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Traits of the Mythic Underworld]]></title>
        <id>https://knightattheopera.blogspot.com/2022/07/traits-of-mythic-underworld.html</id>
        <link href="https://knightattheopera.blogspot.com/2022/07/traits-of-mythic-underworld.html"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T18:10:00.005Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The "Mythic Underworld" is a term popular in the OSR that I believe was coined by Jason Cone in Philotomy's Musings. Cone argued that the rules of OD&D can be interpreted to suggest that the "dungeons" that adventurers delve into aren't really to be understood as real, logical spaces created by normal people or natural processes. Rather, they're more like a surreal, dreamlike, and hostile realm that runs on its own twisted logic, which might be inconsistent. It gives the referee some leeway to make a contrived, game-y, "funhouse" dungeon instead of stressing about accuracy or rationality.

Much of what Cone describes are just traits of megadungeons, or even simply dungeons in general. Things like, "non-linear pathways" and "lots of connections between levels" aren't really mythic, they're …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A Knight at the Opera</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Every so often the best game is no game.]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20187</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/06/30/every-so-often-the-best-game-is-no-game/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-01T01:25:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In which a session of our D&D game is cancelled and we just chatted it up and enjoyed each other's faces.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seasonal Spells]]></title>
        <id>http://hamsterhoard.home.blog/?p=1053</id>
        <link href="https://hamsterhoard.home.blog/2022/06/28/seasonal-spells/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-28T12:33:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Been fighting creative blocks for a while now — I mean, a lot of folks are, I daresay — and it’s been frustrating getting stuck in cycle after cycle of have idea -> ponder idea -> get stuck -> stew in own juices -> get another idea to add to pile -> infinitum. But this … Continue reading Seasonal Spells →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>taichara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stranger Things and "Puzzle Monsters"]]></title>
        <id>https://knightattheopera.blogspot.com/2022/06/stranger-things-and-puzzle-monsters.html</id>
        <link href="https://knightattheopera.blogspot.com/2022/06/stranger-things-and-puzzle-monsters.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-27T04:19:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[[This post will contain spoilers for Stranger Things up through season 4]

The best monsters are not merely a big sack of hit points you hack-n-slash your way through because of a random encounter table. No, they're something more. They have qualities possible only through the conceits of fantasy. They challenge your brain just as much as your stats and dice. They stick in the mind. They're not just a one-and-done encounter. They're grounded in the world and its rules, and can't be understood merely with numbers. And maybe most of all, they're robust enough that reckoning with them is the whole adventure, or at least could be the whole adventure.


A very popular piece of advice in the OSR is "Just Use Bears." The basic argument is that, "monsters which don't have elaborate special abiliti…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A Knight at the Opera</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Morrow Project - Liberation At Riverton, A Review]]></title>
        <id>https://thecosmicorrery.blogspot.com/2022/06/morrow-project-liberation-at-riverton.html</id>
        <link href="https://thecosmicorrery.blogspot.com/2022/06/morrow-project-liberation-at-riverton.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-27T02:37:00.008Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My first meeting with the Morrow Project came in the guise of Different Worlds Magazine, Issue 33 which I inherited along with two issues of Dragon, a copy of the AD&D 1e Players Handbook, Moldvay Basic Set, and a handful of modules. The meeting was brief. A short module featuring a plague carrying biker gang along with some Q&A of the authors. But it wormed the game into my brain and eventually I scrounged pdf's for it out of the corners of the internet and read through them. 


And I was charmed. Its an old, idiosyncratic game but interesting in its presentation of details and has some surprisingly well made modules. So as I reread the Morrow Project's books I will be reviewing them, in hopes that this might introduce other folks to the game. 


Now the obvious place to start would be th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Cosmic Orrery</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MRD2 Nazarite Contracts and MRD2 Updates]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/06/mrd2-nazarite-contracts-and-mrd2-updates.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/06/mrd2-nazarite-contracts-and-mrd2-updates.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-25T14:03:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm a few sessions into my MRD2 Campaign. Scheduling an IRL game is a nightmare or else I'd have liked to be a bit further into the campaign by now, but it's nice to be playing IRL again regardless. I'm realizing now that I've referenced Nazarite Contracts in the PRs and some of the other posts, but have not formally shared anything on them here.


The Nazarite Contracts of MRD2 are equivalent to the Poltergeist Forms of MRD1, the character classes. They are meant to reflect various kinds of careers or skillsets related to careers, but also speak to the psychologies around those careers, what that says about the individual or their relationship with the world.


Mechanically they are mostly the same as Poltergeist Forms, with some changes based on my experiences with my >1 year-long MRD1 C…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calamities for Lost Civilizations]]></title>
        <id>https://glassbirdgames.blogspot.com/2022/06/calamaties-for-fallen-civilizations.html</id>
        <link href="https://glassbirdgames.blogspot.com/2022/06/calamaties-for-fallen-civilizations.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-24T20:52:00.008Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well, things are a bit fucking bleak today, eh? Let's talk about the end times.
Between current events in the US of A, my work on my archeological hearth-fantasy setting, and my revisiting of the storyline of the latest Final Fantasy XIV expansion, I've been thinking a lot about dysfunctional, decaying and all-around disastrous empires and their ends.
All of Ben Robbins' West Marches posts are incredibly useful, thought-provoking, and entertaining reading, but my favorite has always been his musings on Layers of History. I'm trying to invoke this especially in the stuff I'm writing lately, and it always helps to have some jumping off points for the Big Foundational Questions of a setting - the character of the ancient people that came before, and the reason they're no longer here. So here'…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Glass Bird Games</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marvelous Mushrooms - Generator]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.d4caltrops.com/2022/06/marvelous-mushrooms-generator.html</id>
        <link href="https://blog.d4caltrops.com/2022/06/marvelous-mushrooms-generator.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-22T14:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just a quick post sharing a generator I needed to build out for Perchance: Marvelous Mushrooms & Tantalizing Toadstools. Since this one can requires a few rolls, I like to make those a little faster with a generator that can collate content in a click.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>d4 Caltrops</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Loops]]></title>
        <id>https://www.hypertextfish.org/loops</id>
        <link href="https://www.hypertextfish.org/loops"/>
        <updated>2022-06-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[2001: A Space Loop

This post is about how I view procedures as a specific case of gameplay loops (using the video game design term). I want to explore roleplaying through the lens of these loops. Why though? To me the advantage of understanding game loops is intentionally using them in play and design (of systems and adventures alike). By making them explicit (or intentionally subtle) the table can focus on making interesting decisions and narrating the fiction.
Game loops can also inform the base units of your fictional world. Loops that deal with space and time will be better suited for location exploration. While loops that are focused on events and narrative beats are more apt for scene based play.
In a video game, these loops are coded in by the designers, and revealed to us as eithe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Loops</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexflower Lifepath Character Generation]]></title>
        <id>https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/06/hexflower-lifepath-character-generation.html</id>
        <link href="https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/06/hexflower-lifepath-character-generation.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-22T11:53:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes I have thoughts and I have to put them on paper to get them out of my head and get back to the practice of living. This is one of them.
Here, make yourself a BEYOND! THE HYPERTRENCH or Mothership character or something with this. I don't know.
Step 1. Age
Decide how old you are. This determines the number of lifepath hexes you have as well as your starting stats. 
The older you are, the fewer stat points you'll have to work with but the more skilled you will be.



Age (human)

Starting Stat Spread

Number of Hex Steps


Juvenile (<20)

+2, +2, +3, +4

3


Young Adult (20s)

+1, +2, +3, +4

4


Experienced (30-40s)

+0, +1, +2, +3

5


Aged (50-60)

+0, +1, +1, +2

6


Venerable (70+)

+0, +0, +1, +2

7



Step 2. Trace your Lifepath
Next, based on how many hex steps you have, ch…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rise Up Comus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Even Is a “Procedure”?]]></title>
        <id>5fc42d3b9955c744b550776c:5fc449cf7acac6192a4958a4:62abb5785455df5558264046</id>
        <link href="https://www.prismaticwasteland.com/blog/what-even-is-a-procedure"/>
        <updated>2022-06-21T12:56:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So a game has “procedures” but what does that mean? This post presents a 
basic definition for an aspect of TTRPGs that is garnering more and more 
critical attention.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>W. F. Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep Country : The Guano Isles]]></title>
        <id>https://thecosmicorrery.blogspot.com/2022/06/deep-country-guano-isles.html</id>
        <link href="https://thecosmicorrery.blogspot.com/2022/06/deep-country-guano-isles.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-21T00:26:00.003Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Out where deep country meets deep water, on a handful of rocky islands under the baking sun, layers of bird shit strata have hardened into rich, white gold. Blasted, chipped, and shoveled out. Loaded into freighters to take back to Bastion where it becomes saltpeter, fertilizer, and all manner of products. 


Among the innumerable sea birds might be found...


1-4: d8 Convict Shovelers - STR 13, 3hp, Shovels & Picks (d6), Manacles, Grimy Overalls. Want to escape from this life sentence of grueling labour. Watched over by a lone, surly Guard - 6hp, Whip (d4), Musket (d8), Officious Hat.
1 : Hauling bags of guano down a dangerous cliff to be loaded onto a barge.
2 : Watching a fellow prisoner be whipped for killing a gull.
3 : Fistfighting, a distraction so that another convict can steal a s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Cosmic Orrery</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dungeoncrawling Advice for Players]]></title>
        <id>https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/06/dungeoncrawling-advice-for-players.html</id>
        <link href="https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/06/dungeoncrawling-advice-for-players.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-20T16:35:00.010Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s been a lot of good, actionable advice for Referees to telegraph traps, create Jayquays loops, and keep accurate time records. I have seen less advice on how to play a character in an old-school way (although I think the teaching dungeons Tomb of the Serpent King’s and Lair of the Lamb have good player-facing advice). In fact, I think you’d agree that most advice about “play” is geared towards Referees. 

I’m interested in exploring how to be a good player. 



This post is in many ways a sequel to my Player Manifesto, here. 

“The (Egyptian) Book of the Dead is made up of a number of individual texts and their accompanying illustrations. … They served a range of purposes. Some are intended to give the deceased mystical knowledge in the afterlife, or perhaps to identify them with th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rise Up Comus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MRD2 PR 3: You Weren't Supposed to See That Yet]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/06/mrd2-pr-3-you-werent-supposed-to-see.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/06/mrd2-pr-3-you-werent-supposed-to-see.html"/>
        <updated>2022-06-20T14:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previous PRs and general MRD2 context
The Corporation

RegeXperience: “Live for the RegeXperience”. Childishly edgy experimental entertainment and defense company that doesn’t want the world to know what’s really behind their algorithm. EXPERIENCE, ALGORITHM, ENTERTAINMENT


The Manager

Baz Beetz: Infectiously enthusiastic “artiste” and true believer in the company mission who is as profound as nonsensical.


The Cyblessed Liaison

“Tastes like eating out the ass-end of human progress.”: Like a cheap flaccid little candle dripping wax down an otherwise glorious cake wearing a tacky suit reminiscent of a 1980’s faux-wood-paneled station wagon.


The Issue

The Quarterly earnings report is coming up soon, and The Corporation is anomalously underperforming.

Several brand launches this Quart…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sojourner: Orbital]]></title>
        <id>https://www.hypertextfish.org/orbital</id>
        <link href="https://www.hypertextfish.org/orbital"/>
        <updated>2022-06-20T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Homeworld 3 concept art.

Continuing my Sojourner series, I was thinking about an ideal spaceship combat system. Ergo, one where not only the pilot and gunner get all the action. Inspired by Retired Adventurer’s rules, Classic Traveller Book 01 and my Spaceship Submarines I will flesh out the details of spaceships in Sojourner.
Warning. Capital ship exiting jumpspace. Metal hulls scraping against the void. The void screams back, all while it bleeds a midnight star’s blood. Warning. Capital ship exiting jumpspace. You are not prepared. You were not well paid for this either. But you just have to survive until the payday. Warning.
Interstellar Travel
Travel along interstellar routes can be done using star gates. After paying your travel fees to the Empire, you are allowed passage to the next…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sojourner: Orbital</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex’s Questions]]></title>
        <id>http://githyankidiaspora.com/?p=20146</id>
        <link href="https://githyankidiaspora.com/2022/06/19/alexs-questions/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-19T21:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In which I answer questions from Alex concerning the Dungeons and Dragons campaign chronicling the adventures of the Sigil 6.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>juddthelibrarian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>