<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2022-03-19T01:00:53.090Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-03-19T01:00:53.090Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.14.4</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BONUS: Maximum Recursion Depth Exalted Funeral Printing!]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/03/bonus-maximum-recursion-depth-exalted.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/03/bonus-maximum-recursion-depth-exalted.html"/>
        <updated>2022-03-16T11:55:00.003Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maximum Recursion Depth is now available on Exalted Funeral! It should be available print+pdf later today (as of posting). I've been vocal about the fact that I'm a very digitally-oriented person, but I'm still looking forward to having a copy of MRD physically in my hands, and I know many other people do prefer print so I'm glad to have an offering for them. Also, Exalted Funeral is an awesome publisher and it's a real honor to be a part of their catalog. I hope that this exposes more people to MRD and my blog who I would not otherwise have crossed paths with.


Maximum Recursion Depth on Exalted Funeral!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Level Up Everyone and Everything]]></title>
        <id>5fc42d3b9955c744b550776c:5fc449cf7acac6192a4958a4:613d1cbe927160661891602c</id>
        <link href="https://www.prismaticwasteland.com/blog/level-up-everyone-and-everything"/>
        <updated>2022-03-15T13:16:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In most games, the player doesn’t have a choice about what to do with their 
XP. But what if they could invest it into their character, their followers, 
their equipment or anything else?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>W. F. Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alternative Economics (Part 3: Treasure-Driven Adventure)]]></title>
        <id>https://knightattheopera.blogspot.com/2022/03/alternative-economics-part-3-treasure.html</id>
        <link href="https://knightattheopera.blogspot.com/2022/03/alternative-economics-part-3-treasure.html"/>
        <updated>2022-03-13T16:02:00.003Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Return to part 1

Continuing from part 2, I'm exploring some alternatives to the traditional role that money and economics plays in D&D, inspired by real-life situations found in history, with the occasional creative liberty taken here or there to make things more gameable. It's fantasy after all, we're not going to stress about accuracy here. Last time I just talked about small-to-medium adjustments to the existing economic situations your players engage in. This time I want to think bigger picture. In traditional, OSR, "XP for Gold" schemes, dungeoneering is a path that leads to domains being built up for each individual player. But what other campaign arcs shaped by treasure can we imagine?
An important caveat for this: all specific numbers and variables are intentionally left ambiguous…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A Knight at the Opera</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MRD2 Mecha Gear Thematic Spark Tables]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/03/mrd2-mecha-gear-thematic-spark-tables.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/03/mrd2-mecha-gear-thematic-spark-tables.html"/>
        <updated>2022-03-13T14:06:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In moving forward with the idea of using Tarsos Theorem's Concept Crafting for the basis of my Mecha Gear system in Maximum Recursion Depth 2, I have run a series of "Mock Session 0 Playtests", discussing the setting, game mechanics, and character creation with people as if we were going to run a game (and in one case, it actually is going to be an ongoing IRL Campaign!).


I've been pleasantly surprised the extent to which people have responded really positively to the Playtests- it feels like I have demonstrably learned from MRD1 and have gotten better at conveying information and setting expectations, and also in game design itself. One of the playtests was with the first group I ran the earliest version of MRD1, and they said they liked the idea of MRD2 even better and were interested …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blorb: The Technoskald Interpretation]]></title>
        <id>http://technoskald.me/?p=6327</id>
        <link href="https://technoskald.me/2022/03/11/blorb-the-technoskald-interpretation/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-11T17:49:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blorb is a neologism for a particular prep-focused play style that occasionally creates controversy because it means the game world is "real" even before it shows up in a session. Here are my notes on what I think it means.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kyle Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Janus” Mothership Campaign – Session 4]]></title>
        <id>http://technoskald.me/?p=6308</id>
        <link href="https://technoskald.me/2022/03/10/janus-mothership-campaign-session-4/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-10T17:33:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Session alternate title: “Cubic Worsening” The crew this time consisted of: Aeris (Teamster)Billy Ray (Marine)BR3ND4 (Android) Dr Wilson stayed back on the ship, both because the player was unavailable this week as well as because that’s his nature. Narrative The crew finished up some business on Prospero, namely the cyber mod installations for BR3ND4 and … Continue reading “Janus” Mothership Campaign – Session 4 →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kyle Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Follow the Bones]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.symbolic.city/follow-the-bones</id>
        <link href="https://blog.symbolic.city/follow-the-bones"/>
        <updated>2022-03-09T14:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you like quest stories like Gawain and the Green Knight or the Grail cycle, then you may want to check out the new tool I've published...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Session Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random Encounters in the Trollshaws]]></title>
        <id>https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/03/random-encounters-in-trollshaws.html</id>
        <link href="https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/03/random-encounters-in-trollshaws.html"/>
        <updated>2022-03-09T13:37:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm a big fan of random tables. Assuming I curate the table correctly, a random table brings a feeling of exciting realness to the flow of a game - they ensure I'm not just writing a fantasy novel in front of my players.
However, during a game, I can only have so many *things* in front of me. I'm always thinking, "Wait, I know I have a d100 list of books around here, where did I put the Dungeon Alphabet?" In practice, I've become frustrated with how many good tables I know I own vs how many good tables I can bring to hand easily.
I'm trying to solve this problem with technology. I started experimenting with Perchance.
Here is a generator I made to run a Middle-earth game set in the Trollshaws:

If you're looking for a random encounter table to use for your next MERP game, voila! You can st…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rise Up Comus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mausritter Musings]]></title>
        <id>http://technoskald.me/?p=6298</id>
        <link href="https://technoskald.me/2022/03/08/mausritter-musings/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-09T02:18:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We played Mausritter last night and it really felt like, well, playing. Setting matters, even implied setting, and it affects the kinds of stories we can tell.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kyle Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where The Wheat Grows Tall Review]]></title>
        <id>https://newschoolrevolution.com/2022/03/09/where-the-wheat-grows-tall-review</id>
        <link href="https://newschoolrevolution.com/2022/03/09/where-the-wheat-grows-tall-review"/>
        <updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where The Wheat Grows Tall Review]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>New School Revolution</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weird & Wonderful Wavelengths (Variety Show s1e2)]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/03/weird-wonderful-wavelengths-variety.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/03/weird-wonderful-wavelengths-variety.html"/>
        <updated>2022-03-06T15:18:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We interrupt this broadcast of the normally scheduled Weird & Wonderful Worlds blog to traverse the other WWW (the Weird Wonderful Wavelength decomposed like an overzealous cockroach in an empty kitchen from the spectrum of nutrient deficient fluorescent white light that is the World Wide Web). Let us begin with an interactive spacetime courtesy of Leenalchi, from the past, present, future, and sidetime of Korea. But watch out... TIGER IS COMING!




Link here if you don't see the embed on mobile
That sure was something folks. Reminds me of my conversation with Gearoong. Horrific psychedelic Scooby-Don't and the Gang hunting Poltergeists in Maximum Recursion Depth (poor Frieda is already an Ashura).


Moving on to RPGs, because that's why you came here... Right? Or maybe not, sound off fro…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rolling Dice in Call of Cthulhu]]></title>
        <id>http://technoskald.me/?p=6279</id>
        <link href="https://technoskald.me/2022/03/05/rolling-dice-in-call-of-cthulhu/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-06T01:57:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call of Cthulhu has some surprisingly (to me) narrative-focused rules for rolling dice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kyle Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cut-Out Decoration Cards for your Cozy Hole Home]]></title>
        <id>https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/03/cut-out-decoration-cards-for-your-cozy.html</id>
        <link href="https://riseupcomus.blogspot.com/2022/03/cut-out-decoration-cards-for-your-cozy.html"/>
        <updated>2022-03-05T12:54:00.006Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have made a toy.
The equipment cards from Mausritter/Last Gasp Grimoire are so fun. The gimmick is that you print out your equipment cards on card stock and use blue tack to stick them physically onto your character sheet, so you have a sort of Diablo pack experience.
I took this paradigm and applied it to decorations for the cozy hole that you call a home. All artwork is stolen from Mike Ploog's background art in Ralph Bakshi's Fellowship of the Ring.


Choose a decoration for your tiny home.




Place them in your parlor...




...or in your entrance hall.


Click on any of the pictures above - or click here - to download all of the assets. 
Use this for your Mausritter games or maybe even Under Hill, By Water.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rise Up Comus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Janus” Mothership Campaign – Session 3]]></title>
        <id>http://technoskald.me/?p=6256</id>
        <link href="https://technoskald.me/2022/03/04/janus-mothership-campaign-session-3/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-04T16:43:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Mothership shopping session was interrupted by unrest and corporate investigation. You know, like you do.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kyle Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protecting Our Spaces: A Response to Raggi]]></title>
        <id>https://lotbieth.blogspot.com/2022/03/protecting-our-spaces-response-to-raggi.html</id>
        <link href="https://lotbieth.blogspot.com/2022/03/protecting-our-spaces-response-to-raggi.html"/>
        <updated>2022-03-04T14:05:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Somewhere in the 2009-2011 range, when I was just discovering the OSR scene, I ran across a retroclone which stuck out to me and zoomed up into my favorites for quite some time. In contrast to most of the other rulesets I had seen at the time, it had a lot of referee advice -- and it had safety tools. 
No, seriously! They were perhaps a bit rudimentary compared to the codified tools that are out there today, but I didn't see many other rulesets (OSR or otherwise) including quotes like "The Referee shall realize that Rule 0 is for the purpose of establishing the desired atmosphere for his campaign, and not as an excuse to abuse players or a license to be a despot at the game table… The Referee’s role is to challenge players, not victimize them." or "Know your players. Communicate outside of…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Legacy of the Bieth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digging into the original Star Wars RPG]]></title>
        <id>http://technoskald.me/?p=6197</id>
        <link href="https://technoskald.me/2022/03/03/digging-into-the-original-star-wars-rpg/"/>
        <updated>2022-03-03T17:10:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've been thinking about trying to do for Star Wars d6 what Cthulhu Dark did for Call of Cthulhu, or what Into the Odd did for Cypher: break it down to a minimal approach without needing to spend too much time thinking about game rules. As I was looking at this, I started to wonder if it doesn't need anything more than GM attitude. Here’s my first set of thoughts about the game.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kyle Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Tenenbaums meets Children of the Atom: Help me make a storygame!]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/03/royal-tenenbaums-meets-children-of-atom.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/03/royal-tenenbaums-meets-children-of-atom.html"/>
        <updated>2022-03-01T13:52:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had a dream last night (as of when this was drafted, not posted) that got rudely interrupted by construction just as it was wrapping up. It would make a great story that I will likely never write, but could also be a storygame TTRPG. I don't normally play or run storygames, I used to listen to a bunch of Actual Plays of them but honestly at this point don't know much about them, and don't have sufficient time to invest in it, but I would love it if somebody with more knowledge and interest in storygames could help me carry this idea into some small side project. I'm somewhat less gung-ho on this now that it's been several days since I had the dream and this would admittedly be a lot of work, but I do still love this idea and I suspect one way or another this will eventually influence som…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FLoK dev diary: Character Generation]]></title>
        <id>https://tabletopcuriositycabinet.blogspot.com/2022/02/flok-dev-diary-character-generation.html</id>
        <link href="https://tabletopcuriositycabinet.blogspot.com/2022/02/flok-dev-diary-character-generation.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-27T22:05:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Character generation in the original FLoK was deliberately sparse because I had no real idea of what the project was going to be yet. 
It was also one of the areas my playtesters had the most feedback on. Especially the generation of the standard attributes (strength, dex, etc.) was contentious. 
Some disliked that that these tags didn't really come into play, others liked how it informed their idea of their character and the way they roleplayed them. 
This made me consider making some Maze Rats inspired d66 tables to help those who like that input in visualising and roleplaying their character, without suggesting that these are tags which are supposed to come into play.
I also tried to standardise the equipment you get from backgrounds a bit more, allow folks to simply roll up their background and provide some examples of those 'twist' items. All also in d66 tables. 
Here's the current results:


All of this is still subject to revision and I might end up deciding I don't like this form of character generation after all. However, the tables seem like they could be useful all the same, so I might as well share them. 
Next up is probably finishing my write up of GM and Player advise. I've noticed I find it hard to explain what I do quite naturally at the table, so I think I might try an example of play that does everything I tend to do when things go well and see if I can't use that as a basis for writing up the advice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tabletop Curiosity Cabinet</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alternative Economics (Part 2: Interesting Choices)]]></title>
        <id>https://knightattheopera.blogspot.com/2022/02/alternative-economics-part-2.html</id>
        <link href="https://knightattheopera.blogspot.com/2022/02/alternative-economics-part-2.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-27T00:33:00.010Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Return to part 1




I have previously talked at length about the virtues of "campaign-level play." That is, rather than only ever running your game as a series of mostly-isolated scenarios in episodic fashion and then calling it a "campaign," you actually flesh out all the connective tissue between adventures. There are certain gameplay structures you can incorporate which aren't really interacted with on a scenario-to-scenario basis, but which nonetheless have an impact on the campaign as a whole. Examples I give are things like a calendar and downtime play, usable maps and travel gameplay, complicated NPC relationship charts that'll change over time, and of course, domain play and some slightly more in-depth economics than just a menu of regular adventuring gear.

Most of this post's co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A Knight at the Opera</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autopsy Report: Looking back at my first GLoG hack]]></title>
        <id>https://tabletopcuriositycabinet.blogspot.com/2022/02/autopsy-report-looking-back-at-my-first.html</id>
        <link href="https://tabletopcuriositycabinet.blogspot.com/2022/02/autopsy-report-looking-back-at-my-first.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-25T17:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back when I initially started this blog I was working on a GLoG hack for the table I played with at the time. It is somewhat finished, but barely playtested and the few people that did play it seemed to hate it. 
Moreover, this is from before I realised you don't actually need rules for everything, so despite aiming for 'elegant design' it is a rather convoluted mess of rules I thought I'd need because they were so prevalent in other systems, rules I wanted to add because I thought they were missing from 5e and a bunch of systems and mechanics stolen from other blogs merely because they looked interesting.

For these reasons, I don't like looking back at it, it makes me cringe. However, every once in a while when I need an example of something I like, I find myself returning to stuff I wro…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tabletop Curiosity Cabinet</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calendars, Not Just Maps]]></title>
        <id>5fc42d3b9955c744b550776c:5fc449cf7acac6192a4958a4:621812076f54662e8d018384</id>
        <link href="https://www.prismaticwasteland.com/blog/calendars-not-just-maps"/>
        <updated>2022-02-25T14:39:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maps are important for running location-based adventures, but having a 
useful calendar or timeline is equally essential.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>W. F. Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Janus” Mothership Campaign – Session 2]]></title>
        <id>http://technoskald.me/?p=6230</id>
        <link href="https://technoskald.me/2022/02/24/janus-mothership-campaign-session-2/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-25T01:45:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“How do you break an android? You give it feelings.” Elsa (BR3ND4 player) The crew of the Janus arrived at ALCOR Station – basically a truck stop in space – before heading to Prospero. Special thanks to Victor Merino for kindly providing a cleaned-up version of the station image I could share with my players. … Continue reading “Janus” Mothership Campaign – Session 2 →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kyle Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MRD2 Introduction and Campaign Setup Proof of Concept]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/02/mrd2-introduction-and-campaign-setup.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/02/mrd2-introduction-and-campaign-setup.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-24T13:04:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MRD2 is underway, as I've alluded to in previous blog posts. Similar to how much changed between the earliest MRD1 blog posts and the final book, treat this as Proof of Concept, but below is a working draft of the Introduction to the world of MRD2, how it relates to MRD1, and the basic Campaign Setup (an idea I've much appreciated from Anne Hunter). Also, I will definitely clean up the writing significantly- this is not publishing-grade ;).


Previous Posts:

Mecha Gear with Tarsos Theorem Crafting: The basis of the Golem mechanics in MRD2, and also hyperlinks to basically all the previous posts, including the one below.

Jewish American Identity and Jewish Philosophy in Maximum Recursion Depth 2: A discussion on the Jewish subtext of MRD2. Also contains additional relevant links at the en…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Characters and Roles]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.symbolic.city/on-characters-and-roles</id>
        <link href="https://blog.symbolic.city/on-characters-and-roles"/>
        <updated>2022-02-23T02:55:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twice today, entirely by coincidence, I've run across different versions of a claim that might seem uncontroversial, but is worth questio...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Session Zero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conspiracy in the Borderlands]]></title>
        <id>5fc42d3b9955c744b550776c:5fc449cf7acac6192a4958a4:61f09349eefbb34934aa55a0</id>
        <link href="https://www.prismaticwasteland.com/blog/conspiracy-in-the-borderlands"/>
        <updated>2022-02-22T22:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An evaluation of the true villains of the classic adventure: the Cult of 
Evil Chaos, including what they might be up to two hundred years later.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>W. F. Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hand-Crafted Adventures]]></title>
        <id>https://lichvanwinkle.blogspot.com/2022/02/hand-crafted-adventures.html</id>
        <link href="https://lichvanwinkle.blogspot.com/2022/02/hand-crafted-adventures.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-20T16:54:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There was a period of years early in
the hobby’s history when there were no adventure modules at all. In those days,
everybody made their own adventures by hand—without computers. You can,
too.

Lately I’ve returned to the quiet pleasure
of developing hand-crafted adventures and setting materials on my own. I have no
intention of sharing my materials with anybody but the players of my games. I]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lich Van Winkle's Return to Gaming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Janus” Mothership Campaign – Session 1]]></title>
        <id>http://technoskald.me/?p=6222</id>
        <link href="https://technoskald.me/2022/02/19/janus-mothership-campaign-session-1/"/>
        <updated>2022-02-19T17:07:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve recently kicked off a Mothership campaign with friends that focuses more on the stresses of making a living in a capitalist space dystopia than on “horror” in the genre sense. I’m not quite sure what will come of it, but for now we’re having fun. The game takes place two centuries from now in … Continue reading “Janus” Mothership Campaign – Session 1 →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kyle Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MRD Campaign PENULTIMATE Play Reports]]></title>
        <id>https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/02/mrd-campaign-penultimate-play-reports.html</id>
        <link href="https://weirdwonderfulworlds.blogspot.com/2022/02/mrd-campaign-penultimate-play-reports.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-19T14:41:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After >1yr, we've decided to wrap up our MRD campaign. I was developing the MRD core book simultaneously, so this campaign informed a lot of the tone, setting, and content that went into the final book. While we very early on deviated from the core structure of Poltergeist Investigation -> Court Crawl, I'm happy that we got to do some of that, while also demonstrating how this system and setting can support much more than just that. There's a lot of stuff I've written on my blog that isn't in the core book, but it's become a rich and interesting setting, and I'm very grateful for it.


One of my players will be starting a new campaign with this group using his own modified version of MRD, so we're not done! And additionally, I'm hoping to start an in-person game soon for MRD2 as I continue…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weird &amp; Wonderful Worlds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Million Swords]]></title>
        <id>https://slightadjustments.blogspot.com/2022/02/one-million-swords.html</id>
        <link href="https://slightadjustments.blogspot.com/2022/02/one-million-swords.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-19T02:43:00.007Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[img.gallery { 	width: 100% } figure.gallery { 	text-align: center } 
 		Seven of Swords - Ride-Waite tarot deck
Combat
Victory is not achieved by skill (attack bonuses) or luck (high dice rolls). Each combatant takes turns bidding things they are willing to sacrifice to help them achieve victory. Combat ends when one side surrenders, or when they risk their life in pursuit of victory, and fail.

Whoever says "I attack!" first, goes first.
They bid what resources they are staking on their victory. They can bid innate qualities or training, relevant equipment, situational advantages, and things they are willing to sacrifice. The initial bid can't be changed after this step.
Their opponent must meet or exceed that bid with their own resources (qualities, equipment, advantages, sacrifices). If…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Slight Adjustments</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Million Swords]]></title>
        <id>https://slightadjustments.blogspot.com/2022/02/one-million-swords.html</id>
        <link href="https://slightadjustments.blogspot.com/2022/02/one-million-swords.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-19T02:43:00.007Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[img.gallery { 	width: 100% } figure.gallery { 	text-align: center } 
 		Seven of Swords - Ride-Waite tarot deck
Combat
Victory is not achieved by skill (attack bonuses) or luck (high dice rolls). Each combatant takes turns bidding things they are willing to sacrifice to help them achieve victory. Combat ends when one side surrenders, or when they risk their life in pursuit of victory, and fail.

Whoever says "I attack!" first, goes first.
They bid what resources they are staking on their victory. They can bid innate qualities or training, relevant equipment, situational advantages, and things they are willing to sacrifice. The initial bid can't be changed after this step.
Their opponent must meet or exceed that bid with their own resources (qualities, equipment, advantages, sacrifices). If…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Slight Adjustments</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RPGs and Creative Constraints: What’s behind the OSR and FKR?]]></title>
        <id>https://quarterlingscorner.blogspot.com/2022/02/rpgs-and-creative-constraints-whats.html</id>
        <link href="https://quarterlingscorner.blogspot.com/2022/02/rpgs-and-creative-constraints-whats.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-18T18:05:00.006Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I.


Before RPG design became my main hobby, I used to write poetry. My favorite book on my shelf from that time is The New Book of Forms by Lewis Turco. It explains the fundamental building blocks of poetry (such as what “iambic pentameter” means) and lists, in encyclopedic fashion, all the notable forms within English poetry.


Most modern poetry is free verse, including all the poetry I ever wrote. You put the words together however you think they sound good. There are certain principles to absorb that’ll help you with that, but it’s ultimately up to your intuition of what feels right.


It wasn’t always that way. For various historical reasons — because poetry used to be primarily for performance, because it used to be set to music, etc. — poems almost were almost always composed withi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Quarterling’s Corner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Taverns Need a Procedure]]></title>
        <id>5fc42d3b9955c744b550776c:5fc449cf7acac6192a4958a4:61e0d721c686d110ba5031f6</id>
        <link href="https://www.prismaticwasteland.com/blog/your-taverns-need-a-procedure"/>
        <updated>2022-02-18T14:06:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I propose a procedure for running TTRPG taverns less like a beginner’s 
improv class and more like the Mos Eisley Cantina. I also briefly describe 
the trend of “proceduralism” in the OSR and Post-OSR.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>W. F. Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Darkness Strewn with Gems: Session Recaps, LotB Campaign]]></title>
        <id>https://lotbieth.blogspot.com/2022/02/a-darkness-strewn-with-gems-session.html</id>
        <link href="https://lotbieth.blogspot.com/2022/02/a-darkness-strewn-with-gems-session.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-17T21:23:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After many years, I've finally gotten my brains together enough to start running a Legacy of the Bieth campaign again. It's brief spurts -- 2-3 hours over Discord -- but I need to bite off small chunks to get my head in the game (and make sure I'm adapting properly to the schedule). 
I'm adapting Gus L's Tomb Robbers of the Crystal Frontier as the introductory dungeon. TRCF does a really good job at tapping into some of the Roadside Picnic-meets-spaghetti-western feel that I've craved over the years. I've had to use a bit of elbow grease to make details fit with my own setting, but of course that's going to be the case with any module! The core ruleset is currently a modification of  "Savage World of Krul," created by Hydra Coop colleague Robert Parker. 
The game is drop-in/drop-out, so no…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Legacy of the Bieth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>